# Ladan Torkzaban

# Junior Software Developer

#### **Profile**

I'm a full stack developer who has trained with Makers Academy developing my engineering skills. After being a full-time mum to two children for past five years, I have decided to learn coding and I had the privilege to extend my knowledge with Makers Academy and gained a real satisfaction in problem solving and collaboration as well as ability in learn new programming languages such as Ruby and JavaScript in short amount of time.

I have a strong desire to learn code, I love breaking down a project into little piece then used them to build something new out of it.during my coding journey I had this satisfaction as an individual and in a team project. The ability to work in an environment that could build a better future is something I greatly look forward to.

# **Experience**

### Makers Academy (June 2022 to October 2022)

Learnt how to utilise pair programming, Test Driven Development and Object Oriented Design to develop software with high quality code (and ensure it is easy to read and change).

Programmed in Ruby, JavaScript, Node.js and React but learnt how to translate into any language (can't wait to do this more).

Experienced using multiple frameworks, use of Restful APIs and integrating with databases like MongoDB, mySQL and Postgres

Developed passion for learning new technologies & languages, working as part of an agile team and problem solving with tight deadlines.

Skill: Ruby, JavaScript, Node, HTML, CSS, SQL, MongoDB, TablePlus, RSpec, Jest, Cypress, Sinatra, Express

## The Bay Tree (2009 to 2016)

Director Manager

- Book-Keeping
- · Cash and Orders handle
- Update till software

#### **Personal Skills**

## **Quick Learner**

I am good at understanding a concept and use my knowledge to get a project started then build upon that .For example learning Ruby and use it in Bank challenge in my Makers time.

### **Adaptable**

Having coded prior to Makers Academy I was excited to challenge my skills and be open to learning brand new technologies. Few weeks into the course our cohort introduced to JavaScript as well as Ruby, It was a great insight to OOP principles and I was quickly able to adapt and echo my skills onto different projects and technology.

#### **Team Player**

I genuinely enjoy working with others and always finding my place in a team. The Makers course led us to work as on individual and joint projects,, and I was comfortable with either arrangement. One of my strengths is ensuring that everyone has the opportunity to put forward their ideas so that we identify the best solution most effectively.

## **Detail-Oriented**

I have developed an extremely keen eye for the fine details. This comes through in my coding, from seeing how the whole code fits together to finding that one tiny bug. While we had peer group every morning during Makers I used to help my group mate to find those little bugs which stopped their program function well.

#### **Education**

### UWS Glasgow (2012 to 2018)

**BSc Network Communication** 

Key modules - Object Oriented Programming, Web server side programming, Mobile user development